My friend Barry
我的朋友巴里
I'm telling you,
我告诉你，
that creature's fooling us.
那家伙在耍我们。
There are still traces.
还有痕迹。
We won't be fooled any longer.
我们不会再上当了。
Give me the goat.
把山羊给我。
Here.
给你。
Not like that!
不是那样！
Why not like that?
为什么不能那样？
Not like this.
不是这样。
-Sideways!
-The wolf doesn't care!
——侧着拿！——狼才不管呢！
Are you kidding me?
你在开玩笑吗？
We'll catch him this time!
这次我们一定能抓住他！
We got him!
我们抓住他了！
You're hungry too, aren't you?
你也饿了吧？
Come!
过来！
-I'm coming!
-We got him!
——我来了！——我们抓住他了！
Goddammit!
该死！
Impossible!
不可能！
Come on!
快点！
That's enough!
够了！
Come. Enough is enough!
过来。适可而止！
Where have you been?
你去哪儿了？
I was worried.
我很担心。
I fought a wolf!
我跟狼打了一架！
Yeah, right...
是吗，得了吧……
Sure!
当然！
And I even won!
而且我还赢了！
Tomorrow will be another tough day.
明天又是艰难的一天。
Can't we rest a little longer here?
我们不能在这儿多休息一会儿吗？
Come on, we're almost there.
快走吧，我们快到了。
One more day until we reach the pass,
再过一天就能到山口了。
then another day or two
再过一两天
on the other side into the valley.
翻过山谷的另一边
And then we're at the sea.
我们就到海边了
Then we're in Italy.
然后我们就到了意大利
Where it's warm.
那里很暖和
There are no soldiers there?
那里没有士兵吧？
No French people, that's for sure.
肯定没有法国人
And if they do show up,
就算他们来了
the Austrians will kick their asses!
奥地利人也会把他们揍跑！
Good.
太好了
We'll find work.
我们会找到活干
The rich people in the big cities
大城市里的有钱人
-need servants.
-Servants?
需要佣人——佣人？
Yes.
是的。
We're getting our own room.
我们会有自己的房间
Just for the two of us.
就我们俩的
A real bed.
一张真正的床
And you...
还有你……
You'll even get a new scarf.
你还能得到一条新围巾
Tell me about the sea.
给我讲讲大海吧
It's bigger than where we live, right?
它比我们住的地方大，对吧？
Bigger than Lake Lucerne.
比卢塞恩湖还大
A hundred times bigger.
大一百倍
So big
大得
that you can't see the other shore.
看不到对岸
And there are fish
还有鱼
as big as calves...
跟小牛犊一样大……
And it's warm.
而且海水是暖的
And when you lie on your back
当你仰面躺下
and stretch out your arms,
伸开双臂
the water will carry you all by itself.
水会自己托着你浮起来
We just have to get
over the pass tomorrow.
我们只要翻过明天的山口就行了。
And then we'll have
a better life in Italy.
到了意大利，日子就会好起来。
We can do it.
我们能做到的。
Come on!
快点！
Austrian soldiers.
奥地利士兵。
What are they doing here?
他们在这儿干什么？
Kick the asses of the French, right?
打法国人屁股，对吧？
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
We're almost there.
我们快到了。
Alfons!
阿尔方斯！
I can't go on anymore!
我实在走不动了！
Let me see.
让我看看。
Finally!
终于来了！
Where am I?
我这是在哪儿？
In the hospice.
在收容所里。
You slept for two days straight.
你整整睡了两天。
Where's Alfons?
阿尔方斯呢？
I have to take you to the kitchen
我得带你去厨房。
as soon as you're awake.
你一醒就得去。
You're awake now!
你现在醒了！
Put your clothes on.
把衣服穿上。
I'll wait outside.
我在外面等你。
Come on now!
快点儿！
Did you try to steal again?
你又想偷东西了？
-You're getting fatter and fatter!
-Come, Patch, come.
——你越来越胖了！——过来，帕奇，过来。
Come.
过来。
The kitchen is this way.
厨房在那边。
-Hi.
-Hello, Resi.
——你好。——你好，雷西。
This is my father.
这是我父亲。
His dogs are the best avalanche dogs
in the world.
他的狗是全世界最棒的雪崩搜救犬。
They've saved many lives.
它们救过很多人。
Come! I have to take you to the kitchen.
快！我得带你去厨房。
Hurry up before they do
something stupid.
趁他们还没干蠢事，赶紧的。
Resi!
Resi！
I need a new bandage.
我需要一个新的绷带。
Come in the afternoon.
下午过来吧。
Brother Medicus will be back then.
到时候梅迪库斯兄弟会回来。
But it's already quite loose.
但这已经很松了。
It won't heal properly like that.
那样是长不好的。
This tiny cut?
就这点小伤口？
Just leave alone,
then it'll heal by itself.
放着不管，它自己就会愈合的。
-Where's Alfons?
-Who?
——阿尔方斯在哪？——谁？
Alfons, my brother.
阿尔方斯，我哥哥。
-Hey!
-Great shot.
——嘿！——好球。
Come on, leave those monkeys alone.
行了，别去招惹那些猴子了。
Brother Pietro.
皮耶特罗兄弟。
Hello, my dear!
你好，亲爱的！
He needs a warm soup.
他需要一碗热汤。
Sure!
当然！
Go ahead, give it to him.
去吧，给他端过去。
I don't have time.
我没时间。
A bowl of soup!
一碗汤！
Resi is a lovely girl, but...
蕾西是个可爱的姑娘，但是……
How do you say...
该怎么说呢……
She's a stubborn girl.
她是个固执的姑娘。
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
George.
乔治。
Sit down.
坐下。
A good soup...
一碗好汤……
Here you go... enjoy!
给你……慢慢享用！
Eat!
吃吧！
And then we'll see what we do with you.
然后我们再看看怎么处置你。
I want to see my brother.
我要见我哥哥。
Your brother?
你哥哥？
Yes.
是的。
We arrived two days ago.
我们是两天前到的。
What?
什么？
Your brother...
They all left for Italy.
你哥哥……他们都去意大利了。
Two days ago.
两天前。
No!
不！
Sonny!
Your soup...
桑尼！你的汤……
Alfons!
阿尔方斯！
You wanted to see me, Prior?
你想见我，普莱尔？
I'm supposed to be in the library.
我本该在图书馆的。
That's the boy from the last trek.
那是上次远足时遇到的男孩。
His brother has
travelled on without him.
他的兄弟已经独自继续前行了。
Where is he from?
他来自哪里？
Emmental.
埃门塔尔。
Emmental, Prior.
埃门塔尔，普里奥。
His name is George.
他叫乔治。
I want to go to Italy.
我想去意大利。
To my brother.
找我哥哥。
They boy's crazy.
那男孩疯了。
You can't cross the pass on your own.
你一个人过不了山口的。
I'll wait for the next trek.
我会等下一趟远足队。
This was the last
trek you travelled with.
这是你随行的最后一趟远足了。
Until spring.
等到春天。
Until spring?
等到春天？
That means...
-That means you're staying here
那意味着……——那意味着你要待在这里
till the snow has melted.
直到雪融化。
What about your parents?
你父母呢？
Your name is George, right?
你叫乔治，对吧？
George,
you'll make yourself useful here.
乔治，你在这儿能帮上忙。
Brother Pietro is always happy
to have extra help.
皮耶罗兄弟总是乐意有额外的帮手。
Work never stops up here.
这里的工作永远停不下来。
Is there any way to accommodate the boy?
有没有办法安置这个男孩？
-You mean... in the novices' quarters?
-Yes.
——你是说……放在见习修士宿舍？——是的。
Heavens above...
老天爷啊……
There's no free bed?
没有空床了吗？
Prior, with all due respect,
普里奥，恕我直言，
we can't put a farm boy with
the novices. It'll cause unrest.
我们不能把一个农家男孩和见习修士们放在一起。这会引起骚动。
Our discipline! How will
我们的纪律！当……
the parents and patrons react when...
家长和赞助人会怎么反应？
I. I will find a place for him.
一、我会给他找个地方。
Fine.
好的。
George, you'll do the jobs given to you.
乔治，你要完成交给你的任务。
You help out where help is needed.
哪里需要帮忙，你就去哪里搭把手。
Okay?
Our job is to serve.
明白吗？我们的职责就是服务。
I expect diligence,
obedience and humility.
我希望你们做到勤勉、服从和谦逊。
You will fit in while you are with us.
在这里期间，你们要融入进来。
Do you understand that?
明白了吗？
You guys are huge!
你们个头真大！
It's okay, I won't hurt you.
别怕，我不会伤害你们的。
I've never seen such big,
beautiful dogs.
我从没见过这么高大漂亮的狗。
I won't hurt you.
我不会伤害你们。
Yes. Everything's fine.
是的，一切都好。
What a lively bunch you are!
你们可真热闹！
Hey, don't bite.
嘿，别咬。
Hey, you.
嘿，说你呢。
You cheeky bugger!
你这调皮鬼！
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了？
Is something wrong?
出什么事了吗？
You're so weak!
你太弱了！
Dad!
爸爸！
Voilà. Come!
Get out of there!
瞧！快出来！
You can't sleep here.
你不能睡在这里。
And certainly not in the litter box.
更不能睡在猫砂盆里。
Yes, Stella.
好的，斯特拉。
The mother can be very dangerous
母狗在护崽的时候
if you get too close to her puppies.
靠近小狗会很危险。
Yes, I know
是的，我知道
but it kept me warm.
但那里暖和。
This isn't a dormitory!
It's a stable.
这里不是宿舍！是马厩。
Why isn't he drinking?
他为什么不喝酒？
He can't fight for his place.
他无法争取到自己的位置。
The others keep pushing him away
其他人一直在排挤他，
and he's getting weaker and weaker.
他变得越来越虚弱。
He probably won't survive.
他可能活不下去了。
Who gave you this ammonite?
这块菊石是谁给你的？
It's a stone snail.
这是石蜗牛。
That's a fossil.
那是化石。
Of an animal that lived on earth
a long time ago.
属于很久以前生活在地球上的一种动物。
It's a lucky charm.
这是个幸运符。
Alfons gave it to me.
是阿尔方斯送给我的。
And it's a stone snail!
而且它还是一只石蜗牛！
Where did they assign you to work?
他们安排你在哪里工作？
With Brother Pietro.
和皮耶特罗修士一起。
You'll help me with the dogs,
你干完厨房的活后，
when you're done in the kitchen.
就来帮我照看狗。
George, right?
你叫乔治，对吧？
Julien.
朱利安。
Here you go, something delicious.
来，给你点好吃的。
Not so fast!
慢着！
Did you eat the scraps yourself?
你是不是自己把剩菜吃了？
Leave me alone!
别管我！
Oh, thank you!
哦，谢谢！
Can I take the boy along with me?
我能带这个男孩一起走吗？
I'll bring him back, don't worry.
我会把他带回来的，别担心。
Alright.
好吧。
George.
乔治。
Come!
来吧！
Go ahead!
你先走！
You go on.
你继续走。
Me?
我？
I have to peel onions?
我得剥洋葱吗？
Work is work.
工作就是工作。
Lord, help me.
老天，帮帮我。
Watch out!
小心！
You have to walk close to the wall here.
这里你得贴着墙走。
So, what happens with him now?
那他现在会怎么样？
With whom?
谁？
With Stella's puppy
that's not getting any milk.
斯特拉那只喝不到奶的小狗。
It won't survive.
它活不成了。
And Stella will eat him.
斯特拉会把它吃掉。
Nature does what it has to do.
大自然自有其规律。
Enough talk.
别说了。
Work is calling.
工作还在等着呢。
Come.
过来。
I'll bring him back, Stella.
我会把它带回来的，斯特拉。
I can't just let him die.
我不能眼睁睁看着它死。
What on earth are you doing?
你到底在干什么？
Why aren't you sleeping?
你怎么还不睡？
Get out of here!
出去！
How cute!
真可爱！
What are you doing
with him in my kitchen?
你把它带到我厨房里干什么？
Julien says
朱利安说
that he's going to die.
它快死了。
Because nature does what it has to do.
因为大自然自有其规律。
Nature. Nature
大自然。大自然
doesn't know everything.
也不是什么都懂。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
There!
好了！
Now take him back to the stable.
现在把它带回马厩去。
Thank you!
谢谢！
Come.
过来。
You need to drink.
你得喝水。
I promised your mother
that you wouldn't die.
我答应过你母亲，你不会死的。
Here.
给你。
George?
乔治？
Yes?
嗯？
We have to get firewood.
我们得去捡柴火。
-What! Now?
-Yes, now!
——什么！现在？——对，就现在！
Brother Pietro will
get very angry if there
如果明天早上厨房里柴火不够，
-isn't enough wood in the kitchen
tomorrow morning. -Okay.
——皮耶罗兄弟会非常生气的。——好吧。
What's the matter?
怎么了？
I'm coming.
我来了。
I can't wait forever!
我可不能一直等下去！
Let's try again later.
我们晚点再试一次。
I'll be right back.
我马上回来。
Hey, Matteo!
嘿，马泰奥！
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
You can't do that!
你不能那样做！
Let me out!
放我出去！
I have to get out of here! Hey!
我得离开这里！嘿！
You'd rather be
with the pigs in the barn, right?
你宁愿和谷仓里的猪待在一起，对吧？
But maybe they don't want you there.
但也许它们不欢迎你。
Let me out!
放我出去！
Here you go, an onion.
给你，一个洋葱。
Unpeeled.
没剥皮的。
In case you get hungry.
万一你饿了。
Hey!
嘿！
Matteo!
马泰奥！
Sorry.
对不起。
You have to let me out.
你必须放我出去。
Matteo!
马泰奥！
I have to get out of here!
我得离开这里！
Let me out!
放我出去！
Wait!
等等！
Leave me alone.
别管我。
Please don't tell on me!
求你别告发我！
You're still alive!
你还活着！
Go ahead, drink!
来，喝吧！
You're drinking. Great!
你在喝酒？太好了！
Sonny!
桑尼！
Where were you?
你刚才去哪儿了？
I'm sorry.
对不起。
I overslept.
我睡过头了。
No!
不！
Not in my kitchen!
别在我的厨房里磨蹭！
No dawdling in my kitchen.
我的厨房里不许拖拖拉拉。
Got it?
明白了吗？
Go!
快走！
Thank you.
谢谢。
What?
什么？
You stole it?
你偷的？
I helped him.
我帮了他。
But Dad said...
可是爸爸说……
Stella didn't eat him!
斯特拉没吃他！
He was with you the whole time!
他一直跟你在一起！
Wait! Where are you going?
等等！你要去哪儿？
I have to tell my dad.
我得去告诉我爸。
Can't you...?
你就不能……？
I have to feed him.
我得喂他。
He's not strong enough yet.
他还不够强壮。
Have you given him a name yet?
你给他起名字了吗？
A name?
名字？
Yes, he needs a name.
对，他需要个名字。
What name would you like?
你想叫他什么？
I didn't quite get that.
我没听清。
Brother Pietro would call him Piccolo.
皮耶罗修士会叫他皮科洛。
In a few weeks, he'll be about this big.
再过几周，他就能长到这么大。
And anyway,
the name must begin with a B.
而且，名字必须以 B 开头。
B?
B？
Why?
为什么？
That's just the way it is.
规矩就是这样。
Each litter needs to start with
a different initial letter.
每窝小狗的名字首字母都要不同。
The last puppies were called
Alma, Achim, Arno and Alva.
最后几只小狗分别叫阿尔玛、阿希姆、阿尔诺和阿尔瓦。
And now it's B's turn.
现在轮到 B 了。
B... B...
B……B……
How about Benno?
叫本诺怎么样？
Boring!
太无聊了！
Balthasar or...
巴尔塔萨或者……
Bartholomew.
巴塞洛缪。
Way too long, you can't shout that.
太长了，喊起来不方便。
Balthasar!
巴尔塔萨！
Bartholomew!
巴塞洛缪！
More like... Flash.
不如叫……闪电。
Benedict?
本尼迪克特？
Heavens above!
天哪！
What do you think of Biter?
你觉得“咬咬”怎么样？
But he's not a biter, is he?
可它又不咬人，对吧？
Bear?
叫“熊”？
What happens when a real bear shows up?
要是真来了一头熊怎么办？
And we call for the dog...
我们喊狗的时候……
What about... Barry?
叫……巴里怎么样？
Barry?
巴里？
Yes, Barry.
对，巴里。
Fearless Barry.
无畏的巴里。
Barry the protector.
守护者巴里。
Barry!
巴里！
Good morning, Barry.
早上好，巴里。
Hello, Barry.
你好，巴里。
Did you sleep well?
睡得好吗？
You have to be very quiet.
你得非常安静。
No one must discover you.
绝不能让人发现你。
Okay?
好吗？
I'll be back.
我会回来的。
You can't come with me, Barry.
你不能跟我走，巴里。
You have to stay here.
你得留在这里。
I haven't got time right now.
我现在没时间。
Stay here and wait, okay?
待在这儿等着，好吗？
I'll be back soon.
我很快就回来。
That's my book! Give it back.
那是我的书！还给我。
It was under the desk.
它刚才在桌子底下。
Did I allow you to touch it
with your dirty fingers?
我允许你用脏手碰它了吗？
Do you smell it too?
你也闻到了吗？
And do you know what it is?
你知道那是什么吗？
You can't see it,
你看不见它，
but you can smell it.
但你能闻到它。
When you grow up with it,
it sticks to you.
从小闻着它长大，它就会黏在你身上。
You'll always be a country bumpkin
who stinks of cow dung.
你永远是个浑身牛粪味的乡巴佬。
And no book in the world
will ever change that!
世界上任何书都改变不了这一点！
Italy.
意大利。
Does this lead south?
这条路通往南方吗？
Yes, when the snow has melted.
是的，等雪融化之后。
Have you ever been there, in Italy?
你去过意大利吗？
I came to Italy across the sea.
我漂洋过海来到意大利。
From Africa.
从非洲来的。
And why are you up here?
那你为什么待在这山上？
I got a job at the hospice.
我在收容所找了份工作。
No one up here has a problem
在这山上，没人会在意
if your fur isn't white.
你的皮毛是不是白色的。
Like with the dogs.
就像那些狗一样。
It's the work that counts.
干活才是正经事。
Did you ever want to go back?
你曾想过回去吗？
Home?
家？
We've found a place here.
我们在这里找到了一个地方。
Resi and I.
我和瑞茜。
If you're lucky,
如果你足够幸运，
you will find yours too.
你也会找到属于你的。
Let's go!
我们走！
At these stone towers
在这些石塔旁
travellers can get their bearings.
旅行者可以辨明方向。
I thought the pass was closed?
我以为隘口关闭了？
It is!
确实关闭了！
A... A... Abor... Montal...
阿……阿……阿博……蒙塔尔……
Are you reading to Barry?
你在给巴里读书吗？
Hey, Barry.
嘿，巴里。
I'm sure he likes it.
我肯定它喜欢听。
Even though he can probably read better
than you.
尽管它认字可能比你还强。
As if you could read.
说得好像你会认字似的。
The streets are so clean
街道如此干净
that women walk there all year round
女人们一年四季
in slippers.
都穿着拖鞋走在上面。
There are two rows of trees
运河两岸
planted on both sides of the canals.
种着两排树。
Did you never go to school?
你从没上过学吗？
There's no teacher in our village.
我们村里没有老师。
Sometimes
有时候
the pastor taught us something
冬天农活不多时，
when there wasn't much work to do
on the farms in winter.
牧师会教我们一些东西。
Come on, I'll show you.
来，我教你。
It's easier if you memorise
把单词当作图像来记
the words as images.
会更容易。
That's how I did it.
我就是这么学的。
If you want to travel
in the Netherlands,
如果你想在荷兰旅行，
you do so on canals...
就得走运河……
Why the Netherlands?
为什么是荷兰？
The book's about Italy, isn't it?
这本书讲的是意大利，对吧？
It's a travel book.
这是一本游记。
From the Netherlands
从荷兰开始。
via Germany
途经德国
and here, Switzerland,
而这里，瑞士，
all the way to Italy.
一路延伸到意大利。
Why can you read?
你为什么能阅读？
Because I learned it.
因为我学过。
From your mother?
跟你母亲学的？
My mother has passed away.
我母亲已经去世了。
Brother Medicus taught me.
是梅迪库斯兄弟教我的。
I need to be able to read.
我必须学会阅读。
I want to become a nurse.
我想成为一名护士。
You're already a good nurse.
你已经是个好护士了。
I know.
我知道。
Shall we go on?
我们继续吗？
Let's go on!
继续吧！
But in winter, the canals mark...
但在冬天，运河会结冰……
Great!
太棒了！
Barry!
巴里！
And so they were buried...
于是他们被埋葬了……
The paths are not equally safe.
这些路并非同样安全。
Barry!
巴里！
Now you want to play?
你现在想玩吗？
Do you want to play?
你想玩吗？
Aosta.
奥斯塔。
Look, Barry!
看，巴里！
There's the sea.
那里是大海。
And persuaded him by much coaxing
用尽甜言蜜语说服了他，
to guide us to the island.
让他带我们上岛。
Avalanche!
雪崩！
I'm coming with you!
我跟你一起去！
I can help!
我能帮忙！
Julien!
朱利安！
We need all hands on deck.
我们需要所有人手。
Fine. Go on.
好，去吧。
Where did the avalanche come down?
雪崩是从哪里下来的？
Further down,
再往下，
on the Italian side.
在意大利那边。
Julien, look! There!
朱利安，看！那里！
Search, Bella!
Yes!
搜，贝拉！对！
Here?
这里？
Here is something!
这里有东西！
Search!
搜！
Look!
看！
-Schnell!
-Here!
-快点！-这里！
Here!
这里！
Give me a hand!
搭把手！
I've got him.
我抓住他了。
Help pulling!
帮忙拉！
Slowly. Be careful!
慢点。小心！
Pull!
拉！
I've got him!
我抓住他了！
He's alive.
他还活着。
Blanket!
毯子！
Are you alright?
你还好吗？
Can you talk to me?
能跟我说话吗？
Thans. Thank you very much.
谢谢。非常感谢。
Well done!
干得好！
How many people are injured?
有多少人受伤？
I don't know!
我不知道！
You'll have to ask Resi.
你得去问蕾西。
Certainly not!
当然不行！
George, you know where to put it.
乔治，你知道该放哪儿。
Here he comes.
他来了。
Who let him out?
谁放他出来的？
I'll take care of the dogs.
我来照顾这些狗。
You're off duty.
你下班了。
George?
乔治？
Well done.
干得好。
We can use you up here.
我们这里需要你。
That country bumpkin's
so full of himself.
那个乡下佬真是自以为是。
Come on. Go now!
行了，快走吧！
Why? He hasn't harmed me.
为什么？他又没伤害我。
No one will find out that it was you.
没人会知道是你干的。
But I don't want to!
可我不想！
Since when do you get to decide
什么时候轮到你来决定
what you want or don't want?
你想或不想？
Coward!
懦夫！
Get off me, get off!
放开我，放开！
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Julien!
朱利安！
George stole the dog!
乔治偷了那条狗！
He hid it in his room!
他把它藏在自己房间里了！
It was George!
是乔治干的！
Where have you come from?
你从哪儿冒出来的？
George stole the dog!
乔治偷了那条狗！
It is the Lord's will
that His creatures must die.
上帝旨意下，祂的造物终有一死。
And it is His will
when it should happen.
何时发生，也由祂定夺。
This applies to us humans.
But it also applies to animals.
这适用于我们人类，也适用于动物。
That's not true, Prior.
修士，这话不对。
Oh, it isn't?
哦，不对吗？
If...
如果……
If someone is in distress and...
如果有人身处困境……
and we can help,
而我们又能施以援手，
then that's also God's will, isn't it?
那岂不也是上帝的旨意？
You said that we're here to serve.
你说过我们生来就是为他人服务的。
I didn't just feel sorry for him.
我不仅仅是为他感到难过。
Well, yes, that too.
嗯，是的，也有这个原因。
I felt sorry for him
when Stella didn't feed him.
斯特拉不喂他的时候，我挺心疼的。
But he'll help a lot of people
when he grows up.
但他长大后能帮助很多人。
George.
乔治。
Brother Benedict told me
that you stole this book
本尼迪克特修士告诉我，这本书是你
from the library.
从图书馆偷来的。
What did you want to do with it?
你想用它做什么？
Answer!
回答！
I wanted it so I could learn to read.
我想要它，这样我就能学认字了。
Alright, then read.
好吧，那就读吧。
When the sea was very rough,
当海面波涛汹涌时，
we came to a gondolier
我们遇到了一位船夫，
who was trying to pull his boat
out of the waves
他正试图把船从浪涛中拉出来，
and we compelled him...
我们强迫他……
Okay. I think we got it.
好了，我想我们明白了。
The dog will immediately
return to the barn,
那条狗会立刻回到谷仓，
where it belongs, with its own kind.
回到它该待的地方，和它的同类在一起。
Barry.
巴里。
The dog's name's Barry.
那条狗的名字叫巴里。
Barry...
巴里……
And you won't commit another offence.
你不会再犯错了。
Do you understand?
明白了吗？
Yes, Prior.
明白了，院长。
Brother Benedict...
本尼迪克特修士……
From now on, George will participate
in studies with the novices.
从今以后，乔治将和新手们一起学习。
Prior...!
院长……！
And do give him some decent clothes!
还有，给他弄些像样的衣服！
You're right, George.
你说得对，乔治。
We're here to serve.
我们是来服务的。
You lied to me.
你骗了我。
I didn't lie to you.
我没有骗你。
I just didn't tell you everything.
我只是没有告诉你所有事情。
When did we stop
telling each other everything?
我们是从什么时候开始不再对彼此毫无保留的？
Resi.
蕾西。
What's wrong, darling?
怎么了，亲爱的？
I don't like being alone all the time.
我不喜欢总是孤零零一个人。
You're not alone.
你并不孤单。
Except for Pietro,
the monks don't talk with me.
除了彼得罗，那些修士都不跟我说话。
And the stupid novices...
还有那些愚蠢的见习修士……
They just look down on me,
except when they have a scratch
他们总是看不起我，除非他们受了伤
and need some ointment.
需要药膏的时候。
And you...
还有你……
You're always working,
你总是在干活，
in the stable or in the mountains.
不是在马厩就是在山上。
And in the evening,
when you come home, you're tired.
到了晚上，你回到家时已经累坏了。
Of course I'm alone.
我当然很孤单。
Ever since we've been here...
自从我们来到这里……
Since Mom passed away.
自从妈妈去世以后。
And now George is here
and I get on well with him.
现在乔治来了，我和他相处得很好。
You two...
你们俩……
You really had me fooled.
真把我骗得够呛。
And you even got a place at school.
你甚至还争取到了上学的名额。
I want you to keep training Barry.
我希望你继续训练巴里。
Come on, get in there!
来吧，进去！
Did you hear that, Barry?
听到了吗，巴里？
Listen carefully to what George
is going to tell you.
仔细听乔治要跟你说什么。
I'll make a good dog out of you.
我会把你训练成一条好狗。
You've done a good job.
你做得很好。
And I ate well.
我也吃得很好。
Of course!
当然！
Study well and don't
be afraid of the novices.
好好学习，别怕那些见习修士。
Oh no...!
哦，不……！
Gentlemen.
各位先生。
He's supposed to be a novice now?
他现在应该是个见习修士了吗？
Can a cow dance?
牛会跳舞吗？
Barry!
巴里！
Heavens above!
天哪！
I haven't got time now.
我现在没时间。
I'll come back to you after school.
放学后我再回来找你。
Gentlemen!
先生们！
Silence.
安静。
Gentlemen.
先生们。
Come here, Barry, come!
过来，巴里，过来！
Come!
过来！
Sit, Barry!
坐下，巴里！
You have to obey now, Barry.
你现在必须听话，巴里。
Heavens above.
天哪。
Like a stork with a twisted beak.
像只歪嘴的鹳鸟。
Go on.
继续。
George!
乔治！
Would you like to try?
你想试试吗？
Yes, good.
嗯，不错。
You can sit on a cushion.
你可以坐在垫子上。
This is a Moroccan tagine with lemon.
这是摩洛哥柠檬炖锅。
How are things going at school?
学校那边怎么样？
Heavens above!
天哪！
Do you want to be a teacher too?
你也想当老师吗？
They're all so clever.
他们个个都那么聪明。
Would you like to come too?
你也想来吗？
Ask the prior.
去问院长吧。
A girl among the novices.
见习修士里有个女孩。
They" all become monks one day.
他们总有一天都会成为修士。
And anyway, what would I do
among these clever monkeys?
再说了，我跟那些聪明猴子混在一起能干什么？
Soon you'll be one of them.
你很快也会成为他们中的一员。
I won't!
我才不要！
Yes, you will!
你会的！
No, I won't!
我不会！
You can sleep at night.
你晚上能睡个好觉。
Listen. you have to work
especially hard
听着，你必须特别用功，
otherwise you'll always be a farm boy.
Do you understand?
否则你永远只是个乡下小子。明白吗？
-It's over, I won!
-Yeah...
——结束了，我赢了！——嗯……
That's right, you cheated!
没错，你作弊了！
What have we learned, Barry?
Come!
我们学到了什么，巴里？过来！
Turn around, follow me.
转身，跟我走。
And now, sit!
现在，坐下！
Well done!
干得好！
-Come, Bella. Come.
-Barry, come.
——过来，贝拉。过来。——巴里，过来。
Hey! Good man,
嘿！好伙计，
You shouldn't rest here.
你不该在这儿休息。
My son is in Switzerland.
我儿子在瑞士。
Have to cross the pass.
必须翻过这个山口。
Come.
过来。
Get some soup from the kitchen! Go on!
去厨房弄点汤来！快去！
-Hurry!
-Come, Barry!
——快！——过来，巴里！
Hot!
烫！
Don't spill everything on the table!
别把东西全洒在桌上！
Watch out!
小心！
I don't have time!
我没时间了！
No time!
没时间了！
No, Barry, wait!
不，巴里，等等！
Is there anything left in the bottle?
瓶子里还剩什么吗？
I'm sorry.
对不起。
That mustn't happen to you again!
你可不能再出那种事了！
Come on!
快点！
Come, Barry!
过来，巴里！
What's he doing?
他在干什么？
He doesn't seem to be hungry.
他好像不饿。
Barry, come to me.
巴里，到我这儿来。
Just try it on. Come on!
先试试看。来吧！
If it doesn't fit,
I'll take it off again.
要是不合身，我再脱下来。
Very good.
很好。
What do you think, Barry?
你觉得怎么样，巴里？
Now the soup can't spill anymore.
现在汤不会再洒出来了。
Even if the rescuers are slow
就算救援人员动作慢，
or get stuck somewhere.
或者被困在什么地方。
Or stumble, like I did.
或者像我一样摔倒。
Yes, Barry.
对，巴里。
George?
乔治？
For you.
给你的。
For me?
给我的？
From Italy.
来自意大利。
Dear George,
亲爱的乔治，
A comrade is writing this letter for me.
一位同志替我写了这封信。
Perhaps a monk will read it to you.
也许会有位修士读给你听。
I hope the stone snail
has brought you luck.
希望石蜗牛给你带来了好运。
I'm sorry I couldn't stay with you.
很抱歉没能和你在一起。
Imagine,
the Austrians promised me more pay
想想看，奥地利人答应给我的报酬
than the two of us can earn in a year.
比我们俩一年挣的还多。
As a soldier, I got boots and a gun.
当兵后，我领到了靴子和枪。
We're waiting for the war to start
我们正等着战争开始
against the French.
对抗法国人。
We have lots of time and little food.
时间很多，食物很少。
When the war is over,
等战争结束，
I'll come and get you.
我就来接你。
Alfons.
阿尔方斯。
George.
乔治。
We'll show him
what we're capable of.
我们会让他见识见识我们的本事。
What's going on?
怎么回事？
What's this?
这是什么？
Give it back.
还给我。
-Oh, a love letter!
-Give it back!
——哦，一封情书！——还给我！
Give it back!
还给我！
Oh! From the brave soldier
who abandoned you.
哦！来自那个抛弃你的勇敢士兵。
My family's none of your business.
我的家事与你无关。
A soldier in the Austrian army...
一个奥地利军队的士兵……
That's what you call family?
这就是你所谓的家人？
And where's your family?
那你的家人在哪儿？
Why are you up here?
你为什么要待在上面？
My family...
我的家人……
My family pays for everything here.
这里的一切都是我家人付的钱。
You're being fed here
thanks to my family.
你在这里吃饭，全靠我的家人。
That you don't have to sleep in a pigsty
is thanks to my family.
你不用睡在猪圈里，这得感谢我家。
You country bumpkin!
你这个乡巴佬！
Is spring finally coming?
春天终于要来了吗？
The spring storms will come first.
春天的暴风雨会先到来。
The worst of the cold weather is over.
But the avalanches...
最冷的天气已经过去了。但雪崩……
Stay together.
待在一起。
The snow's unpredictable
when it gets warmer.
天气变暖时，雪况难以预测。
But he can become quite unpleasant.
但他有时会变得相当不讨人喜欢。
If Brother Benedict gives you a mean
look, the class immediately freezes.
如果本尼迪克特修士投来严厉的目光，全班立刻鸦雀无声。
But he's a nice teacher as long as...
但他是个好老师，只要……
Hey! A wolf.
嘿！有狼。
A wolf!
有狼！
Go behind the rocks!
躲到岩石后面去！
Barry! Come back here.
巴里！快回来。
Come on, George!
快过来，乔治！
-Leave the dog alone!
-Barry!
-别管那只狗！-巴里！
Come back!
快回来！
Come on, George!
快过来，乔治！
Come back!
快回来！
He won't harm us.
它不会伤害我们的。
George.
乔治。
-Everything okay?
-George!
-没事吧？-乔治！
Well done, Barry!
干得好，巴里！
-George, everything okay?
-Yes.
-乔治，没事吧？-没事。
-How did you do this?
-What did you do?
-你是怎么做到的？-你做了什么？
No, how did you do that?
不，你是怎么做到的？
I don't know.
我不知道。
You know that this was dangerous,
what you did up there.
你知道刚才在上面做的事有多危险。
We trusted each other.
我们互相信任。
You've made a good dog out of him.
你把它训练成了一只好狗。
He's the best!
它是最棒的！
For you.
给你的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I prayed that something would happen.
我祈祷能发生点什么。
-Like that a rock would fall on the wolf.
-And suddenly...
-比如有块石头砸中那只狼。-然后突然……
it became dead quiet.
四周变得死寂。
George and Barry... they just
stood there, in front of a wolf.
乔治和巴里……他们就那样站在一头狼面前。
-A real wolf?
-The atmosphere was very strange.
——真狼？——气氛非常诡异。
George! Come over here.
乔治！到这边来。
So small, but so brave!
个头虽小，却如此勇敢！
I almost wet my pants.
我差点吓尿裤子。
I'd never have dared to do that.
我可绝不敢那么做。
The French are coming!
法国人来了！
Napoleon's soldiers!
拿破仑的士兵！
A little dignity, gentlemen. Dignity!
拿出点尊严来，先生们。尊严！
Good evening, captain.
晚上好，上尉。
Welcome to our hospice.
How many soldiers are you?
欢迎来到我们的收容所。你们有多少士兵？
For the moment just my section.
But others will come.
目前只有我这一队。但其他人会来的。
How can you even talk to them?
你怎么能跟他们说话？
In French.
用法语。
It doesn't matter where they're from.
We're giving them shelter.
他们来自哪里并不重要。我们给他们提供庇护。
That's what the hospice is for.
这就是收容所的用途。
But they're soldiers.
可他们是士兵。
Frenchmen!
法国人！
They destroy everything in their path.
他们一路烧杀抢掠。
Your brother's a soldier too.
你哥哥也是士兵。
Alfons is out there
and he's going to fight the French.
阿尔方斯就在外面，他要去打法国人。
And I don't know if he...
我不知道他是否……
He doesn't have the stone snail anymore.
他不再有石蜗牛了。
It always brought him luck.
那东西一直给他带来好运。
Now I have it.
现在它在我这里。
He'll run away if it gets dangerous.
遇到危险他会逃跑的。
Do you think so?
你这么认为吗？
Yes. He runs away and comes back to you.
是的。他会逃跑，然后回到你身边。
Everything will be fine.
一切都会好起来的。
We have to leave at dawn
我们必须在黎明时分出发
otherwise we won't get to the wedding
in Italy by daylight.
否则就赶不上白天在意大利举行的婚礼了。
That's Celestin's father,
那是塞莱斯坦的父亲，
Mr von Wydler,
冯·维德勒先生，
and his sister,
还有他的妹妹，
Miss Florence.
弗洛伦斯小姐。
Tomorrow, everyone will
travel on to Italy for a wedding.
明天，所有人将继续前往意大利参加婚礼。
Celestin too?
塞莱斯坦也去吗？
...out there in the wild valleys,
……在那荒凉的山谷里，
in wind and weather.
任凭风吹雨打。
Just a few days ago
就在几天前，
we rescued a group of poor pilgrims,
我们救了一群可怜的朝圣者，
when suddenly
突然之间，
a huge wolf stood in front of me.
一头巨大的狼站在我面前。
A huge animal with bulging eyes
那庞然大物双眼圆睁，
and enormous teeth.
獠牙巨大。
I ordered Barry to stand with me
in front of the wolf.
我命令巴里和我一起站在狼面前。
The wolf was so confused,
那狼被弄得晕头转向，
that he tucked his tail between his legs
and ran away.
夹着尾巴逃跑了。
You should have seen that.
你真该亲眼看看。
Would you like to see Barry?
你想见见巴里吗？
Father, may I go with him?
父亲，我能跟他去吗？
If Brother Benedict allows you to.
如果本尼迪克特兄弟允许的话。
He has relieved me of my duties.
他已经解除了我的职责。
Hey, you fool!
嘿，你这个笨蛋！
I'm sorry!
对不起！
Hurry up and clean that up!
赶紧把这里清理干净！
Move. Come on! Get up!
动起来。快点！起来！
-You're hurting him!
-You have to show them who's boss.
——你弄疼他了！——你得让他们知道谁说了算。
That's the only way they'll obey.
只有这样他们才会服从。
Stupid animal!
愚蠢的动物！
Sit! Off!
坐下！滚开！
Stupid animal!
愚蠢的动物！
Get out!
滚出去！
Come on, Florence!
快点，弗洛伦斯！
Let's leave this country bumpkin.
我们离开这个乡下土包子吧。
Are you alright?
你还好吗？
-Do you want to pet him?
-Is he...
-你想摸摸他吗？-他是不是...
-May I?
-Yes.
-可以吗？-当然。
He's very well-behaved!
他非常乖！
Barry's the best dog in the world.
巴里是全世界最棒的狗。
If I had a dog,
如果我养狗，
I'd never hit it.
绝不会打它。
It would have to be just like Barry.
它必须得像巴里一样。
We'd be friends, you and me.
我们会成为朋友，你和我。
Best friends.
最好的朋友。
Why do you need that?
你为什么要那个？
For the journey.
路上要用。
Where is he?
他在哪儿？
I couldn't do anything, George.
我无能为力，乔治。
Where's Barry?
巴里在哪儿？
In the stable,
with the soldiers.
在马厩里，和士兵们在一起。
He's going with Florence tomorrow.
他明天要和弗洛伦斯一起走。
He belongs here!
他属于这里！
In the mountains!
属于这片山！
Von Wydler is an influential man.
冯·维德勒是个有影响力的人。
Florence will take good care of him.
弗洛伦斯会好好照顾他的。
You don't know that!
你又不知道！
They may not take Barry away.
他们可能不会带走巴里。
George, choose another dog.
乔治，换一条狗吧。
No!
不！
George!
乔治！
Pietro!
皮耶特罗！
Barry.
巴里。
Let's go away.
我们走吧。
But you have to be quiet.
但你必须保持安静。
Barry.
巴里。
Quiet.
安静。
Barry.
巴里。
Come.
来。
Sit!
坐下！
Wait!
等等！
They want to take him away from me.
他们想把他从我身边带走。
And where are you going now?
你现在要去哪儿？
They won't take you back.
他们不会带你回去的。
I'm going to Alfons.
我要去找阿尔方斯。
Into war?
去打仗？
I don't want you to...
我不想你……
not be here anymore.
再离开这里。
I have to go, Resi.
我必须去，蕾西。
Do you have your lucky charm?
The stone snail?
你带着幸运符了吗？那只石蜗牛？
Take care of yourself.
照顾好自己。
Goodbye, Barry.
再见，巴里。
Barry, come!
巴里，过来！
We're almost there, Barry.
我们快到了，巴里。
We just have to make it to the hut.
只要撑到那间小屋就行。
Come, get in here!
来，快进去！
We'll be safe here until tomorrow.
在这里待到明天就安全了。
I know you're hungry too!
我知道你也饿了！
Everything's fine.
一切都会好的。
Look, Barry. This...
看，巴里。这里……
is Verona.
就是维罗纳。
Alfons is here.
阿尔方斯就在这儿。
And we're here, in Switzerland.
而我们在这里，在瑞士。
With a few big jumps
再跨几大步
we'll be there.
就能到了。
And if there's not too
much snow in Italy,
只要意大利那边雪不太大，
we'll manage to get there in ten days.
十天之内我们就能到。
It's madness to set off in this fog!
这种大雾天出发简直是疯了！
I told them to wait another day.
我让他们再等一天。
But Mr von Wydler wouldn't listen.
但冯·维德勒先生就是不听。
Damn!
该死！
Barry, we overslept.
巴里，我们睡过头了。
Barry, don't pull so hard!
巴里，别拉那么用力！
Hey, what's the matter?
嘿，怎么了？
Barry!
巴里！
Barry, here you are!
巴里，你在这儿啊！
You?
是你？
Where are the others?
其他人呢？
Florence, and your father?
弗洛伦斯，还有你父亲？
Did he abandon you here?
他把你丢在这儿了？
Certainly not, you idiot!
当然不是，你这个白痴！
Come on!
快点！
No!
不！
I'm staying here!
我要留在这里！
They'll find me.
他们会找到我的。
I'm Celestin von Wydler.
我是塞莱斯廷·冯·维德勒。
You're nobody out here.
Do you understand?
在这儿你什么都不是。明白吗？
Come on,
I'll help you get down to the valley.
来吧，我帮你下山到谷里去。
Leave me alone!
别管我！
I'm not afraid!
我不怕！
Fine, we'll go on to Italy without you.
行，那我们就撇下你去意大利了。
Barry.
巴里。
Come on, Barry, let's go.
走吧，巴里，我们出发。
Is this even the right way?
这条路对吗？
You have no idea where we are!
你根本不知道我们在哪儿！
I knew it was you.
我就知道是你。
Who stole the animal.
偷走那头牲口的家伙。
You mean Barry, who found you?
你是说巴里，那个找到你的人？
We're lost!
我们迷路了！
You and your damn dog.
你和你的那条该死的狗。
We need shelter from the storm.
我们需要找个地方躲避暴风雪。
We have to trust Barry!
我们必须相信巴里！
I can't go on! My leg.
我走不动了！我的腿。
It's too much.
这太难了。
Come on!
快点！
Pull yourself together!
振作起来！
Well done, Barry!
干得好，巴里！
Go ahead. I'll be right there!
你先走，我马上就来！
Where are you going?
你要去哪儿？
Keep going, Barry.
继续走，巴里。
Are you crazy? The book's valuable!
你疯了吗？那本书很值钱！
Would you rather freeze to death?
你宁愿冻死吗？
Where are we?
我们在哪儿？
Somewhere under a glacier.
冰川下面的某个地方。
That was your idea,
那是你的主意，
about Barry.
关于巴里的。
Florence would have taken
good care of him.
弗洛伦斯本来会好好照顾他的。
I know that.
我知道。
But you wanted to take
Barry away from me.
但你想把巴里从我身边带走。
Even though you already have everything.
即使你已经拥有了一切。
You have got everything!
你什么都有了！
Everyone likes you.
每个人都喜欢你。
Julien, Resi
朱利安、雷西，
and you're good with the dogs.
而且你很会照顾狗。
Even Matteo is now your friend.
连马泰奥现在都成了你的朋友。
Since you've arrived...
自从你来了以后……
everyone has begun... to shine.
每个人都开始……发光了。
Why didn't you turn back
when the storm started?
暴风雪开始时你为什么不掉头？
My father said that the weather
would get better in the valley.
我父亲说山谷里的天气会好转。
And the porters didn't say anything?
搬运工们什么都没说吗？
They didn't resist?
他们没有反抗？
You don't know my father.
你不了解我父亲。
My father only sees his business
我父亲眼里只有他的生意。
and Florence with her pretty face.
还有那个脸蛋漂亮的弗洛伦斯。
And my brother,
with his fiancée in Milan.
而我哥哥，则和他的未婚妻在米兰。
I wouldn't want to see myself either.
连我自己都不想看见自己。
An ugly weakling with a crippled leg.
一个丑陋的瘸子。
You're not ugly.
你不丑。
Only when you're mean.
只有刻薄的时候才丑。
Barry.
巴里。
Celestin doesn't make it to the valley.
塞莱斯坦到不了山谷。
We have to go back to the hospice.
我们得回疗养院去。
And when we get back,
等我们回去之后，
we can no longer be together.
就不能再在一起了。
Then you have to go with Florence.
那你得跟弗洛伦斯走。
My father will never find us here.
我父亲永远找不到我们在这里。
Right?
对吧？
No one will find us in here.
没人会在这里找到我们。
Barry!
巴里！
Come!
来吧！
This has to lead somewhere.
这里肯定通向什么地方。
But look...
可是你看……
We can't even really stand.
我们连站都站不稳。
How are you going to climb down there?
你怎么爬下去？
With all that ice?
到处都是冰？
Not climbing...
不是爬……
Are you scared?
你害怕吗？
Of course!
当然！
Me too.
我也怕。
One...
一……
two...
二……
Barry!
巴里！
Come, Barry.
来吧，巴里。
Thanks!
谢谢！
Look!
看！
I can't go on.
我走不动了。
Come on!
快点！
We're almost there.
我们快到了。
It's not far now.
离这儿不远了。
You can hold on to Barry.
你可以抓紧巴里。
Holy Mother of God!
圣母玛利亚！
Help!
救命！
Celestin!
塞莱斯廷！
My son!
我的儿子！
Help!
救命！
Dad.
爸爸。
George!
乔治！
Thank God!
谢天谢地！
Hang in there!
坚持住！
Everything will be fine.
一切都会好起来的。
I'm so glad you're back!
真高兴你回来了！
Everything will be fine.
一切都会好起来的。
You've only got a sprained foot
and a few frostbitten toes.
你只是扭伤了脚，脚趾有点冻伤。
Where's Barry?
巴里在哪儿？
This is a hospital room, you idiot!
这是病房，你这个白痴！
Sorry.
I have to take George to the prior.
抱歉。我得带乔治去见院长。
Now?
现在？
Mr von Wydler and his daughter
want to continue their journey.
冯·维德勒先生和他女儿想继续赶路。
I hear you're well.
听说你康复了。
I'm glad to hear it.
我很高兴听到这个消息。
You stole, George.
你偷了东西，乔治。
And from a patron of
the monastery at that.
而且偷的还是修道院的施主。
What do you have to say about that?
你有什么要说的？
I didn't want Barry
to have to live in a town.
我不想让巴里住在镇上。
I wanted him to stay up here.
我想让它留在这里。
You broke the rules again.
你又违反规矩了。
Prior, with all due respect.
先前，恕我直言。
George saved his comrade's life.
乔治救了他战友的命。
Yes.
是的。
You have shown courage and humanity.
你展现了勇气与人性。
I therefore refrain from punishment.
因此我免去对你的惩罚。
May I...
我能否……
say goodbye to Barry?
与巴里道别？
George.
乔治。
You brought back my son.
你带回了我的儿子。
I can't thank you enough for that.
对此我感激不尽。
So...
所以……
Barry belongs to you.
巴里属于你。
And you belong to him.
而你也属于他。
I'm sorry I wanted to take him away
from you.
抱歉我曾想将他从你身边带走。
Thank you.
谢谢。
One more thing, George.
还有一件事，乔治。
We've decided to accept you as a novice.
我们决定接纳你为见习修士。
Mr von Wydler will cover the costs
of your education.
冯·维德勒先生将承担你的教育费用。
In three years you can join the Order
三年后你可以加入修会
and become a priest.
成为一名神父。
I don't want to become a priest.
我不想成为神父。
Heavens above... George!
天哪……乔治！
I'd like to teach
我想教书
the children in my village
教我们村里的孩子们
everything I've learned here at school.
我在学校学到的一切。
You want to become a teacher?
你想当老师？
Well...
嗯……
Well.
That should be fine with our rules,
嗯。这倒不违反我们的规矩，
that you continue to attend classes
with us
你可以继续来我们这里上课
and become a good teacher.
成为一名好老师。
Barry! Hello!
巴里！你好！
Hello.
你好。
I thought I'd never see you again.
我以为再也见不到你了。
Come, Celestin.
走吧，塞莱斯坦。
-Yes, Barry.
-A fine dog.
-是的，巴里。-真是条好狗。
-Barry, you're the best dog in the world!
-You're such a good dog.
-巴里，你是全世界最棒的狗！-你真是条好狗。
Did you miss me already?
这么快就想我了吗？
George?
乔治？
Alfons!
阿尔方斯！
Is the war over?
战争结束了吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
But it's not my war anymore.
但这不再是我的战争了。
-This is Resi.
-Hello.
-这是蕾西。-你好。
-This is Celestin.
-Hello.
-这是塞莱斯廷。-你好。
And this
还有这位
is my friend Barry.
是我的朋友巴里。
I told you he was going to run away.
我早说过他会逃跑的。
Come!
过来！
I'll take you to Brother Pietro
in the kitchen.
我带你去厨房找皮耶罗兄弟。
We won't let your brother go hungry.
我们不会让你弟弟挨饿的。
Enjoy your meal.
请慢用。
Do you think I can rest for a bit here?
我能在这儿歇会儿吗？
Before we set off on our way?
在我们启程之前？
On our way?
启程？
Home, to the farm.
回家，回农场去。
We'll rebuild it.
我们会重建它。
I'm staying here.
我要留在这里。
What?
什么？
You want to stay up here?
你想留在这上面？
There's nothing here!
这儿什么都没有！
Just snow and ice!
只有冰雪！
I'm going to school here.
我要在这里上学。
With the novices.
和见习修士们一起。
And I'll make sure he stays well-behaved
and focused!
我会确保他保持乖巧和专注！
I will follow you to our village,
我会跟随你回到我们的村庄，
as soon as I've become a teacher.
等我当上老师之后。
George the teacher...
乔治老师……
I always knew you'd turn out to be
a remarkable person.
我早就知道你会成为一个了不起的人。
It brings good luck, doesn't it?
它能带来好运，不是吗？
The stone snail?
石蜗牛？
Actually, it's not a stone snail,
其实那不是石蜗牛，
it's an ammonite.
是菊石。
Nerd!
书呆子！
Do you think others
will also return to the village?
你觉得其他人也会回村吗？
We'll see.
走着瞧吧。
-They won't all have become rich abroad.
-Like you, you mean?
——他们不会都在外面发财了吧。——你是说像你一样？
Hey!
嘿！
First,
首先，
I'll rebuild the stable.
我要重建马厩。
I can shelter with the animals.
我可以和牲口一起住。
And next winter, I'll rebuild the house.
然后明年冬天，我要重建房子。
And then you'll soon be home.
这样你很快就能回家了。
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
I have everything I need.
我什么都不缺。
See you soon.
回头见。
And you,
还有你，
take care of my brother.
照顾好我弟弟。
Take good care of him, alright?
好好照顾他，好吗？
Come, Barry.
来吧，巴里。
Alfons!
阿尔方斯！
When I'm a teacher, I'll come home.
等我当了老师，我就回家。
BARRY LIVED FROM 1800 TO 1814.
巴里生于 1800 年，卒于 1814 年。
HE RESCUED THE LIVES OF 40 PEOPLE.
他拯救了 40 人的生命。